<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Memo Garcia</title>
    <link>https://memogarcia.mx/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Memo Garcia</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2019 07:53:23 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://memogarcia.mx/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>日本 参照カード</title>
      <link>https://memogarcia.mx/posts/japanese-reference-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2019 07:53:23 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memogarcia.mx/posts/japanese-reference-card/</guid>
      <description>ひらがな + カタカナ     a i u e o     - a あ ア i い イ u う ウ e え エ o お オ   k ka か カ ki き キ ku く ク ke け ケ ko こ コ   s a さ サ shi し シ su す ス se せ セ so そ ソ   t ta た タ chi ち チ tsu つ ツ te て テ to と ト   n na な ナ ni に ニ nu ぬ ヌ ne ね ネ no の ノ   h ha は ハ hi ひ ヒ fu ふ フ he へ ヘ ho ほ ホ   m ma ま マ mi み ミ mu む ム me め メ mo も モ   y ya や ヤ  yu ゆ ユ  yo よ ヨ   r ra ら ラ ri り リ ru る ル re れ レ ro ろ ロ   w wa わ ワ    wo を ヲ   - n ん ン               g ga が ガ gi ぎ ギ gu ぐ グ ge げ ゲ go ご ゴ   z za ざ ザ ji じ ジ zu ず ズ ze ぜ ゼ zo ぞ ゾ   d da だ ダ ji ぢ ヂ zu づ ヅ de で デ do ど ド   b ba ば バ bi び ビ bu ぶ ブ be べ ベ bo ぼ ボ   p pa ぱ パ pi ぴ パ pu ぷ プ pe ぺ ペ po ぽ ポ           ky kya きゃ キャ  kyu きゅ キュ  kyo きょ キョ   sh sha しゃ シャ  shu しゅ シュ  sho しょ ショ   ch cha ちゃ チャ  chu ちゅ チュ  cho ちょ チョ   ny nya にゃ ニャ  nyu にゅ ニュ  nyo にょ ニョ   my mya みゃ ミャ  myu みゅ ミュ  myo みょ ミョ   ry rya りゃ リャ  ryu りゅ リュ  ryo りょ リョ   hy hya ひゃ ヒャ  hyu ひゅ ヒュ  hyo ひょ ヒョ           gy gya ぎゃ ギャ  gyu ぎゅ ギュ  gyo ぎょ ギョ   j ja じゃ ジャ  ju じゅ ジュ  jo じょ ジョ   by bya びゃ ビャ  byu びゅ ビュ  byo びょ ビョ   py pya ぴゃ ピャ  pyu ぴゅ ピュ  pyo ぴょ ピョ</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modular CLI Documentation Fuzzy Finder</title>
      <link>https://memogarcia.mx/posts/doc-fzf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2019 15:03:30 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memogarcia.mx/posts/doc-fzf/</guid>
      <description>Fuzzy Search documentation from the CLI.
See it in action here https://terminalizer.com/view/2c3935cf1418
Disclaimer This tool was built to learn FZF capabilities. Feel free to use it or extend it.
Usage doc-fzf ansible doc-fzf ansible -q yum  Installation pip3 install doc-fzf  Verify your installation:
doc-fzf -h usage: doc-fzf.py [-h] [-q QUERY] module_name doc-fzf. positional arguments: module_name Name of the module to search optional arguments: -h, --help show this help message and exit -q QUERY Query the docs  Extending Doc-FZF doc-fzf is a modular application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Richard Feynman videos</title>
      <link>https://memogarcia.mx/posts/richard-feynman/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 22:20:31 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memogarcia.mx/posts/richard-feynman/</guid>
      <description>The World from another point of view
  Fun to imagine
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Waju</title>
      <link>https://memogarcia.mx/posts/waju/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 15:49:47 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memogarcia.mx/posts/waju/</guid>
      <description>Waju or whatever is called is a game that until this day I don&amp;rsquo;t know from where it comes. But, is fun.
Edit: The game is based on a German game called Mensch ärgere Dich nicht
Goal The goal of the game is very simple:
 Move your marbles for one lap from your home to your goal. Don&amp;rsquo;t worry about winning but don&amp;rsquo;t let anyone else win. Have fun.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond PEP 8</title>
      <link>https://memogarcia.mx/posts/beyond-pep8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 18:53:23 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memogarcia.mx/posts/beyond-pep8/</guid>
      <description>Best practices for beautiful intelligible code
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux on Huawei Matebook X Pro</title>
      <link>https://memogarcia.mx/posts/linux-matebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 13:10:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memogarcia.mx/posts/linux-matebook/</guid>
      <description>This laptop has very decent specs:
 8th Generation Intel® Core™ i7-8550U processor GPU: NVIDIA® GeForce® MX150 with 2 GB GDDR5 / Intel® UHD Graphics 620 16 GB LPDDR3 2133 MHz BT 4.1 (compatible with 3.0 and 2.1+EDR) 512 GB NVMe PCIe SSD  Don&amp;rsquo;t expect running workstation level workloads in this machine but it is a wonderful dev machine.
Things I don&amp;rsquo;t like about the laptop  Palm rejection, especially this one, maybe this is Linux.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying OpenStack on Docker</title>
      <link>https://memogarcia.mx/posts/openstack-containers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 May 2018 18:53:14 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memogarcia.mx/posts/openstack-containers/</guid>
      <description>Note This is a Work-In-Progress Document and the most up-to-date information is available at: github.com/memogarcia/openstack-deployer
Deploying OpenStack using containers allows easy customisation and flexibility on how to deploy the platform for development, testing and production environments.
Current deployment: stable/queens
Host configuration The default configuration for this environment is composed by 3 main components that need to run on the host:
 Docker Libvirtd OpenVSwitch  Docker will act as the control plane for OpenStack while the host will provide the hypervisor, network and storage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenSSL Certificate Authority</title>
      <link>https://memogarcia.mx/posts/becoming-ca/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 19:03:30 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memogarcia.mx/posts/becoming-ca/</guid>
      <description>A Certificate Authority or CA is an entity that signs digital certificates. These digital certificates are used to validate the connection while using secure mechanisms.
Generating a root CA We will use a root CA to create intermediate CA&amp;rsquo;s which are trusted to sign certificates on its behalf.
First, prepare the environment.
mkdir /root/ca &amp;amp;&amp;amp; cd /root/ca mkdir certs crl newcerts private chmod 700 private touch index.txt echo 1000 &amp;gt; serial  Then download the template for /root/ca/openssl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pratai, event driven platform for OpenStack</title>
      <link>https://memogarcia.mx/posts/pratai/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2018 19:08:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memogarcia.mx/posts/pratai/</guid>
      <description>Note This is a Work-In-Progress Document.
Read the docs at memogarcia/pratai-docs
Abstract Pratai provides an incredibly flexible and resilient platform to migrate workloads to the cloud that respond to events without having to manage any server or network.
How it works The goal of Pratai is simple. Deploy &amp;ldquo;code&amp;rdquo; (disclaimer, from now on I will refer to code as functions), that will react to an event without worrying about anything else, the platform handles the execution.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>